Iurii Perederii

Saratov, Russia



uyuddar@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/iurii-perederii



+79279152755



https://agnarh.github.io/

Summary

I'm a software developer with 6 years of experience. I specialize in front-end and web technologies but also have an experience in back end as well. I have experience in all stages of the software development life cycle for dynamic web projects. I am able to work across the whole project lifecycle and have experience of working in large teams distributed over the world.

Technical skills:

- Javascript, Typescript, React
- Redux, Sagas, Jest, Enzyme, Webpack
- HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap
- C#, ASP.Net MVC, MSSQL, SSMS
- Confluence, GitHub, GitLab, TFS (Azure DevOps)
- VS Code, Visual Studio, Git Bash, Command Prompt

Relevant experience:

- Communication with the customer
- Clarification of business requirements
- Projects and features development
- Code review skills
- Tasks review and estimations
- Working along Scrum

Languages:

English - Upper-Intermediate (B2)

Russian - Native speaker

Experience



Senior Software Engineer

EPAM Systems

May 2021 - Present (11 months +)

Key developer (Portlet Builder team):

- Proposed and implemented technical improvements
- Conducted demos for the customer
- Clarified requirements with the customer
- Participated in grooming/planning sessions

<epam>

Software Engineer

EPAM Systems

Sep 2020 - May 2021 (9 months)

Key developer (Data Collection Experience team):

- Moved a legacy SPA into current portal and resolved integration and authentication issues
- Participated in releases
- Discussed and clarified requirements with the customer
- Conducted technical demos and demos for the customer
- Participated in grooming/planning sessions

Tech lead on RD project:

- Configured FE project from the scratch (React+Typescript)
- Supervised junior developers
- Performed code reviews
- Established CI pipeline (GitLab)
- Conducted daily meetings
- Communicated with project/team leads

Software Engineer

EPAM Systems

Mar 2019 - Sep 2020 (1 year 7 months)

Key developer (Emerald team):

- Introduced Typescript to the project
- Took responsibility on challenging tasks (Mobile view implementation, FE performance optimization)
- Refactored existing SQL logic to C# for performance optimization (performance gain for the AWS Lambda - 8-10 times)
- Participated in releases
- Participated in Code Reviews
- Participated in grooming/planning sessions
- Played active part in the process of tasks clarification and decomposition with customer

Software Engineer

EPAM Systems

Mar 2017 - Mar 2019 (2 years 1 month)

Developer (Valuation team):

- Successfully convinced and implemented a refactoring of a complicated page in SPA to React+Redux and covered it with unit tests.
- Gradually refactored part of a legacy code base to a modern ES6+ standards and covering it with unit
- Onboarded 4 developers
- Communicated with customer on daily basis
- Participated in grooming/planning sessions
- Conducted daily meetings
- Performed demos for team members and the customer

Junior Software Engineer

EPAM Systems

Apr 2016 - Mar 2017 (1 year)

Developer (Valuation team):

- Partially refactored legacy code
- Participated in code reviews

- Participated in grooming/planning sessions

Education



(iii) Saratov State University named after N.G.Chernyshevsky

Specialist, Theoretical and Mathematical Physics Sep 2005 - Jul 2010